Thanks to this man, many people have seen math again, which they thought was difficult and complicated.
It's a great honor given to mathematicians.
Professor Heo Joon-hee, who received the Fields Award, returned from the awards ceremony last weekend and came out to KBS today.
Let's meet him quickly.
Professor, how are you?
Hello.
I heard that you heard that you were going to receive the Fields Award early this year.
When exactly is it?
I don't remember the exact date, but it was supposed to be delivered to the Russian President, so I think it was just before the war.
So you've been living as a secret mathematician for a while.
How did you feel?
After hearing the news, I thought I should at least talk to my wife, other than other executives and PR people.
I looked for my wife, and she was sleeping because it was late at night.
So I thought for a moment, and when I woke her up and talked to her, she fell asleep again.
Rather than cheering and hugging her, she responded calmly, so I felt good and reassured.
You've seen a lot of domestic reactions, but the process of growth has become a hot topic.
You went to elementary school and university in Korea, but you are evaluated as an exceptional achievement in Korean education, not an achievement achieved by Korean education.
What do you think of yourself?
If I remember my childhood, I was a quiet, introverted, and ordinary child who was not special or special.
After that, I went to elementary, middle, and high school, and I was influenced by many special and outstanding friends and teachers.
I think I've been making myself little by little while learning.
Of course, it wasn't always easy, but as many people do, I learned a lot of things I know now in the first half of my life, growing up in the fence of education.
In that sense, I think it was a very valuable time for me.
It was a valuable experience.
You said that the winding road you walked on was the best path for you.
One of them is that you dreamed of being a poet once, and your favorite poem is the poem of Ki Young-do, Jealousy is My Power.
Why do you like this poem?
At that time, I felt like I was expressing my feelings well, and I had a strong desire to fully understand what was deep inside me.
But I'm sorry to my middle school self, but I think it was because I wasn't treated when I was in middle school.
Looking back, I had a strong desire to become a person who wrote a great poem rather than a desire to write a great poem.
I think I couldn't go far on the road of poetry because I lacked sincerity.
I heard that you thought about becoming a scientist if you couldn't be a poet.
There are scientists in KBS, too.
Why is that?
As a writer, I had a hobby and aptitude for science, so I thought it would be difficult to make a living as a poet, and then I thought of it as a realistic route.
Of course, being a science journalist is a great job, but I personally don't have any regrets.
It's amazing that the route I chose for a realistic reason led me to a better way than the best way I thought at the time, and I'm grateful to myself.
When you came to the airport last week, you met your 8-year-old son, right?
I can see the picture, and I'm sure you went to school.
I'm sure a lot of parents are curious.
Is there a math education method for your father, Heo Joon?
My son, Dan, and I do one math problem a day.
When Dan makes a math problem, I solve it and Dan scores it and returns it.
It's not a big problem.
It's a problem like drawing a few circles and guessing how many circles there are.
I was so good at guessing, so Dan told me to draw as many circles as I could and guess how many there were.
Dan doesn't know math yet, but when he has to count exactly 130 circles,
If I draw 130 circles in 10 lines, I guess there are 130 in total,
and if I draw 130 circles randomly without any rules,
I realize that I made a mistake after suffering for a while.
As a parent, I was very proud.
As you know, Korea is a country that risks its life for math because of the entrance exam.
There are many students who solve the entrance exam well, but there are no real math students.
Why do you think so?
It's a difficult topic.
I think it's because we use our precious school days not to study, but to be evaluated.
I hope that students with aptitude can learn without hesitation without worry that they have to solve it quickly without mistakes.
And I hope that students in their 20s will be well prepared when they go to college and start learning their major.
In the case of students, I'm sure it's a lot of pressure to take the entrance exam that can determine their lives,
but I hope they don't get intimidated and study what they want without making mistakes,
but what they want to study without hesitation.
And I hope that social adults will set up a good system so that the courage of such students will not be betrayed.
I think it's a related story.
Lastly, we asked the viewers in advance.
We prepared a chalkboard and a chalkboard that the professor likes to use and asked for a simple greeting.
I hope you study steadily and happily with a healthy mind.
What did you want to emphasize?
The most important progress in science and mathematics is not to achieve a project that you already understand to some extent,
but to be purely interested and curious.
But in order to have such a pleasant and curious mind,
you have to be healthy and enjoy the act of thinking, so I wrote it in that sense.
I heard that Professor Heo Joon-hee has a notebook that he wrote the role model of his life.
I hope there will be more students who enjoy math with the goal of Heo Joon-hee in the future.
Thank you for coming today.
Thank you.